日  听      マキ
Oh...
日听校对       Syura
You're not eating breakfast?
Mm-mm.
翻译        葉隠
Okay, well, I'm off.
翻译校对       Mam
"School fair day 2- main fair"
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
"Central Building Salon"
朝ご飯食べないの
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
"The Host Club is open for
business to the general public"
诸神字幕组
Welcome.
それじゃ　行ってきます
いらっしゃいませ
You're one of the sons from
the Otori family, right?
あなた　鳳家のご子息なんですってね
But as third son, no matter
how hard you struggle,
でも三男じゃ　どう足掻いても家は継げないわね
you'll never succeed the family.
What would you like today?
本日はいかがいたしましょう
How much of Haruhi Fujioka's debt remains?
ハルヒ藤岡の借金は後どれくらい残ってるの
Haruhi...
ハルヒ
You've been requested.
ご指名だ
By your leave.
失礼します
Tamaki seemed to have quite
a soft spot for you.
あなたずいぶんと環に可愛がられてたみたいね
You mean to say, you are jealous?
それは　つまり　やきもちですか
Well, listen to you.
あら　言うわね
Tamaki won't be coming.
環は来ないわよ
I ordered him not to show his
face again at the Host Club.
もうホスト部には顔を出すなって私が命じたの
I wonder what happened to Tama-chan.
タマちゃん　どうしちゃったのかな
I don't believe the declaration
his highness made yesterday.
昨日の殿の言動を…
納得できないよな
I have decided to get engaged
to Lady Éclair Tonnerre here.
俺はこのエクレール・トネール嬢と婚約することにした
Further, the Host Club will be
dissolved following Ouran Fair.
それから　ホスト部は　この桜蘭祭が終わり次第
解散する
Come on, no more idle chatter.
ほら　無駄なおしゃべりをしているんじゃない
Our guests are waiting.
お客様がお待ちかねだぞ
How cool of you, Kyoya- senpai.
クールだね　鏡夜先輩は
We will entertain to the best
of our ability the guests
このホスト部を楽しみに来てくれたお客様に
who have come to the Host Club
to enjoy themselves.
できる限りのお持て成しをする
That is the most important
thing right now.
それが今一番大切なことだ
He's right, Kao-chan.
そうだよ　馨ちゃん
What are you doing, Honey- senpai!?
何すんの　ハニー先輩
Let's go, Hikaru.
行くぞ　光
Wait, Mori- senpai...
ちょっと　モリ先輩
Thank you for all of the work
you've done for so long, Haruhi.
長い間ご苦労だったな　ハルヒ
With that request from Lady Éclair,
your quota has been met.
今のエクレール嬢の指名で　ノルマ達成だ
The debt for that Renaissance vase
that you broke is now cleared.
ルネの花瓶を割った借金は全てなくなった
You are free to quit being
a host at any time now.
もういつでもホストを辞めていいんだぞ
When you're young, you may be
under the illusion that there
若い頃は時間がいくらでもあるように錯覚するが
is all the time in the world,
but in reality, that is not so.
実際はそうじゃない
Don't go wasting your time
in things that are of no value!
価値のないことで時間を無駄にするんじゃない
In this Host Club...
このホスト部は
Kyoya- senpai works as hard as he can
for everyone to enjoy themselves.
鏡夜先輩は皆を楽しませるために一生懸命やっています
By entertaining everyone,
we also come to feel fulfilled.
皆を楽しませることによって自分たちも豊かな気持ちになります
Is entertaining everyone
really so worthless?
皆を楽しませることはそんなに価値のないことなんですか
I think that Kyoya- senpai
is outstanding.
自分は鏡夜先輩は立派だと思います
So,
そうか　あれが鏡夜の言っていた特待生か
that is the honor student
that Kyoya talks about, is it?
Grand Tonnerre is a dangerous foe,
which has recently been bringing
グラントネール社は
ここしばらく日本企業を次々と傘下におさめている危険な相手ですよ
Japanese businesses under their
umbrella, one after the next.
It is of no matter. Once we have an heir,
いいではないの
縁続きになれば　須王の家もますます栄えるというもの
the Suou family will prosper even more.
After all, the boy cannot
turn against the Suou family.
どうせあの子は須王の家に逆らったりはできない
Tamaki is not all that
interested in the Suou family.
環は須王の家に興味なんかありませんよ
What measures have you employed?
どんな手を使ったんです
I told him that if he becomes
engaged to Lady Éclair,
エクレール嬢と婚約するなら
I would allow him to see his mother.
母親と会わせてやってもいいと言ったんです
You would still...
あなた　未だに…
I am only having your son make amends
お前の人生の不始末を
for the mismanagement of your life.
お前の息子に償わせてるだけです
Tamaki won't be coming.
環はこないわよ
I ordered him not to show his
face again at the Host Club.
もうホスト部には顔を出すなって私が命じたの
Are you Tamaki's lover?
あなた　環の恋人？
No.
違います
I see. Good. Then you're nothing to him.
そう　よかった
あなたは関係ない人なんだ
I am not his lover,
but I am not nothing to him.
恋人じゃありませんが　関係ない人なんかじゃありません
You'd best not have any contact
with your friends for a while.
しばらくお友達とは連絡を取らないほうがいいわ
It will make you reluctant
to leave them, right?
未練が残るでしょう
Come in.
どうぞ
There is a visitor here to see you.
お客様がお見えです
Have them come in.
入っていただいて
Uncle...
おじさん
Why is Tamaki- kun here?
なぜ環君がここに？
Never mind him.
いいのよ　彼は
Nice to see you again, Uncle.
ご無沙汰してます　おじさん
I am the one who asked Kyoya into
the Host Club. I'm sorry. But then,
鏡夜をホスト部に誘ったのは俺です
すいませんでした
Uncle, what are you doing here?
おじさんこそ　なぜここに？
We're terribly sorry to have asked
you to come all the way here.
わざわざこんな場所に足を運んでいただいて
申し訳ありませんでした
On the contrary, I am rather served
by being able to avoid the press.
いや　マスコミを避けられてむしろ好都合だよ
My medical equipment
company is apparently
うちの医療機器会社が
about to be purchased
by Grand Tonnerre over here.
まもなくこちらのグラントネール社に買収されてしまうらしい
It probably serves Kyoya right.
鏡夜こそ　いい面の皮かもしれんな
The company that I was thinking
of transferring to him
あいつに譲ろうと思っていた会社は
will be out of his hands now.
もうあいつの手には入らない
Uncle,
おじさま　早速一つお願いがあるの
I have one request, right off.
What is with this outfit?
なんなんですか　この衣装は
We told you, it's a costume
for the special parade.
だから　スペシャルパレードの衣装だよ
Haru-chan, you look cute!
ハルちゃん　可愛い
Not that. Why am I the only
one dressed as a girl?
そうじゃなくて
何で自分だけ女の子なの
Who cares? This is cosplay,
いいじゃん　コスプレーだから
so dressing like you're
a girl is completely okay!
女装しても全然オーケー
"Like" I'm a girl?
女装ってね
Well?
No good. He's not answering.
ダメだ　出ない
Tamaki- senpai really did
結局　環先輩　今日は一度もサロンに顔出しませんでしたね
end up not showing his face
once at the salon today.
Ah, Shima-san? It's been too long.
This is Kyoya.
ああ　シマさん
"Suou second estate"
お久しぶりです　鏡夜です
This is about Master Tamaki, right?
環坊ちゃまのことですね
The Master will be departing for France.
坊ちゃまはフランスに発たれることになりました
I tried to stop him,
お止めしたのですが
but he said that the Suou family
had forgiven his mother,
須王の家がお母様を許してくださる
and that he could finally
make his mother happy.
やっとお母様を幸せにできると
Also, he said that if he
stayed at Ouran any longer,
それと　これ以上自分が桜蘭にいても自分のわがままで
his capriciousness would only
make trouble for you, Kyoya-sama,
鏡夜様と皆様に迷惑をかけるだけだからと
and everyone else.
That idiot.
あのバカが…
Tamaki is planning to return to France.
環のやつ　フランスへ帰るつもりだ
Tama-chan is leaving!?
タマちゃんいなくなっちゃうの
You've gotta be kidding!
ふざけんなよ
I'm not about to let
this end so suddenly!
こんないきなり終わってたまるかよ
Hikaru...
光
Kyoya-sama...
鏡夜様
Yes?
I, Shima, was thinking,
シマは思うのです
If the Master's mother
is really the sort of lady
坊ちゃまのお母様が
本当にいつも坊ちゃまがお話になっているような方なら
that the Master always spoke of,
then I am sure she would not
be pleased with the manner
きっとこんな形で坊ちゃまが桜蘭を去ることなど
in which the Master is leaving Ouran.
お喜びにならないだろうと
When is he leaving for France?
あいつはいつフランスへ？
His plane is this evening.
今日の夕方の飛行機で
That soon?
そんな急に
He said he would leave Japan tonight,
as the Ouran Fair was ending.
今日　桜蘭祭が終わると同時に日本を発つと
Tamaki!
環
Tama-chan!
タマちゃん
Sir!
殿
The Ouran Fair isn't over yet!
まだ桜蘭祭は終わってないだろう
My family's car should
be in the parking lot!
うちの車が駐車場にあるはずだ
Let's go, Haruhi!
行くぞ　ハルヒ
We are in a hurry. Head out at once.
急いでいる　すぐに出してくれ
きょ…鏡夜様
Kyoya-sama...
What's the matter?
どうした
T-the thing is...
それがですね…
What are your orders?
何を命じられた
Were you ordered
to protect Lady Éclair?
エクレール嬢の護衛でも命じられたか
I am truly sorry that
it has come to this,
こんなことになって本当に残念ですが
but we, the private police,
answer to your father.
私たちプライベートポリスの主はお父様ですから
Damn it!
I'm terribly sorry, but we
cannot allow anyone to leave.
申し訳ありませんが　誰も行かせるわけにはいかないんです
Even if we must do so by force.
たとえ　力ずくでもね
Use the carriage.
この馬車を使え
If you take the back hills bypass,
you can cut them off.
裏山のバイパスを抜ければ先回りできる
It's Haninozuka and Morinozuka...
埴之塚と銛之塚
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
Haruhi,
go get that idiot.
あのバカを頼む
Get going, Hikaru!
行け　光
What are you doing!?
Stop that carriage!
何をする　その馬車を止めんか…
Takashi,
崇
be sure to pull your punches!
ちゃんと手加減しろよ
I know.
分かっている
I told you, picking on
my friends was a no-no!
僕の友達苛めたら　メって言ったでしょう
Don't think you can get the best
of the Ouran Host Club.
桜蘭ホスト部をなめるなよ　お前ら
Hikaru, Kaoru, Haruhi,
光　馨　ハルヒ
bring Tamaki back.
環を頼んだぞ
Hikaru! This much speed
is reckless, to say the least!
光　このスピードいくらなんでも無茶だよ
We're bringing his highness
back, no matter what!
殿は絶対連れ戻す
Hikaru...
光…
If it weren't for his highness, we would
still be left out of this world!
もし殿がいなけりゃ
僕たちは世界から置き去りにされたままだった
It's because of the Host Club
that we were able to meet Haruhi,
ホスト部のおかげでハルヒにも会えたし
and become so close
to everyone else, too!
皆とも仲良くなれた
Having the Host Club
end as suddenly as this...
そのホスト部がこんないきなり終わっちゃうなんて
...is something that I couldn't take!
僕は絶対いやだ
Hikaru!
光
Hikaru... Hikaru...
光　光
Hikaru, are you okay?
Does your arm hurt?
光　大丈夫？　腕痛いの？
Damn it all...
ちくしょう…
Is this really how we're
going to end, sir?
僕たち…本当にこんな風に終わっちゃうのか
殿…
Hikaru...
光…
Okay, well, I'm off.
それじゃ　行ってきます
Is it something that talking
to your dad won't help?
お父さんに話してみても力になれないこと？
え？何で？
Why do you ask?
Really, I just don't want
to eat this morning, that's all.
今朝は本当に食べたくないだけ
After your mother's funeral,
it took some time
あんた　お母さんのお葬式の後も
before you were able to eat
breakfast again, too, right?
朝ご飯食べられるようになるまで時間かかったでしょ
I won't ever be able to see Mom again?
もうお母さんには会えないの
There certainly are a lot
of things in this world
世の中には頑張ってもどうにもならないことが確かにいっぱいある
that you can't do anything about,
try though you might.
Remember, Haruhi,
いいこと　ハルヒ
this is exactly why you can't hesitate
when it's time to stick things out.
だからこそ
頑張らなきゃいけない時は躊躇ったりしちゃ駄目なのよ
Haruhi?
ハルヒ
瞬きを繰り返す古く色褪せた
Taking the same road home as always,
What's the matter?
You haven't said anything.
どうしたの　黙り込んじゃって
Taking the same road home as always,
You're a host, aren't you?
Entertain me.
あなた　ホストなんでしょう
街灯に導かれていつもの帰り道を行く
led by the constant blinking
of old, faded streetlamps
You're a host, aren't you?
Entertain me.
もっと楽しませてよ
led by the constant blinking
of old, faded streetlamps
What about you? Are you really
okay with getting engaged
君こそ
家に命じられて　会ったばかりの男と婚約するするだなんて
led by the constant blinking
of old, faded streetlamps
to a man that you just met,
on orders from your family?
A familiar breeze blows
through this rusty old town
to a man that you just met,
on orders from your family?
錆びれた街に懐かしい風が吹き
本当に平気なのか
A familiar breeze blows
through this rusty old town
It becomes a favorable wind,
pushing at my back
追い風になって背中押すんだ
I'll keep this despair within my heart
涙枯れるまでその諦め胸に仕舞ってSTOP!
'til the tears dry up and stop!
There is no goal!
ゴールはないぜ　折り返しもないぜ
No turning back, either!
I tear through the wind and sprint
along in an endless dash
風を切って駆け抜ける限り無い疾走
I tear through the wind and sprint
along in an endless dash
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
I tear through the wind and sprint
along in an endless dash
Haruhi Fujioka?
ハルヒ藤岡…
What are you doing, Haruhi!?
何してる　ハルヒ
It's too dangerous!
Stop the carriage, now!
危ないから　早く馬車を止めろ
Senpai! Please come back!
先輩　戻ってきてください
Look, just stop the carriage!
いいから　馬車を止めるんだ
Nobody wants you to leave, Senpai!
皆　先輩に行ってほしくないんです
But, everyone says that they
are put out by the Host Club...
けど…皆ホスト部で　迷惑してるって
Senpai, you really are an idiot.
A blithering idiot!
先輩は本当にバカです　大バカです
After as long as we've been together,
こんなに長く付き合っていて
Let's return those bitter days
can't you even tell when we're
joking or being serious!?
Let's return those bitter days　開けてみないか
冗談か本気かも分からないんですか
Wouldn't you like to open
We all like being in the Host Club!
皆ホスト部が好きなんです
this Pandora's box with
our dreams locked inside?
We all like being in the Host Club!
夢閉じ込めたパンドラの箱を
this Pandora's box with
our dreams locked inside?
We really like it!
本当に好きなんです
this Pandora's box with
our dreams locked inside?
Even I...
自分も…自分もホスト部が好きです
this Pandora's box with
our dreams locked inside?
Even I like being in the Host Club!
this Pandora's box with
our dreams locked inside?
Go first or go second, either way,
先手後手どちらとてコマ進めりゃ万事OK!
once you move, everything's OK!
You can even take a break!
休んでもいいぜ　俺は知ってるぜ
I know how it is!
The whole process up
to now is your witness.
ここまでのプロセスそれが君の証しさ
The whole process up
to now is your witness.
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
The whole process up
to now is your witness.
With my right hand, and my
left hand, held over my head,
右手左手振りかざして闇を切り裂いてGO!
I tear through the darkness and go!
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
Senpai!
先輩
What a reckless thing to do.
Look, you're soaking wet because of it.
なんって無茶をする
見ろ　おかげでびしょ濡れだ
That doesn't matter, does it?
いいじゃないですか
Like they say, "a man dripping
with good looks," right?
水も滴るいい男って言うでしょ
Tama-chan! Haru-chan!
タマちゃん　ハルちゃん
Sir!
殿！
Geez, what a moron.
ったく　あの馬鹿が
Drive on.
出して頂戴
Éclair-sama, you heard all those stories
from that one housekeeper, right?
エクレールさまはあの家政婦からずっと聞かされていましたね
About her son, who always
played the piano for her?
いつもピアノを弾いてくれたという息子さんのことを
Is he really that nice a boy?
そんなに優しい男の子なの
Thank you.
ありがとう
And here, I was going to let
him see his mother again.
せっかく母親に会わせてあげようと思ったのに
The fool...
バカなやつ
Still, just for me,
でも　こんな私のために
he smiled.
彼…笑ってくれた
I'm sorry for having
caused you concern.
心配をおかけしましたがね
Grand Tonnerre has turned
away from my company.
グラントネール社はうちの会社から手を引きましたよ
An unexpected backer turned up,
思わぬ助っ人が現れて
acquired the company
before Tonnerre could,
トネール社よりも先に買収し
and then said that he was turning
all management rights over to me.
そして経営権を全て私に譲ると言ってきた
That was quite bold.
Which fund manager was it?
それはまた豪気な
どこのファンドマネージャーです
A student investor, named "K.O."
KOという学生投資家です
He cleverly kept his name out of it,
but I eventually learned who it was.
巧妙に名前を伏せていましたが
ようやく正体が分かりました
"K.O."
KO…鏡夜　鳳
"Kyoya Otori."
It was none other than my own son.
何のことはない　うちの息子ですよ
This is what's meant
by being afraid for the future.
末恐ろしいとはこのことだ
I thought I knew how brilliant
Kyoya- kun was, but...
鏡夜くんが優秀なのは知ってるつもりだったが
No, your son is the one
who is truly amazing.
いや　本当に凄いのはお宅の息子さんだ
I am the one who gave
Kyoya his education.
鏡夜を教育してきたのはこの私だ
I knew that he was more brilliant
than his older brothers.
あいつが兄たちより優秀なのは知っていた
However, while the Kyoya that
I know might take over a company,
だが　私の知っている鏡夜なら乗っ取るようなことはしても
he wouldn't do anything
like give it all back to me.
それをそっくり返すようなことはしませんよ
I brought Kyoya up all this time
dangling the carrot of taking over
私は鏡夜に
鳳家の経営する会社の跡継ぎという餌を
the companies managed by
the Otori family in front of him.
ずっとちらつかせて育ててきた
But not only has he taken
it from me by force,
しかし　あいつは…
それを実力で奪い取った上で
he said he didn't want it,
and thrust it right back in my face.
いらないと言って　私の鼻先に突き返してきたんです
Do you understand what that means?
これがどういうことか分かりますか
He has found it.
あいつは見つけたんですよ
Something that has even
greater value to him.
それ以上に価値のあるものを
And it is probably thanks to Tamaki- kun.
おそらくは環君のおかげで
We have come to be somewhat
competitive with each other,
あんたとは何かと競合してきたが
but from now on, maybe we'll
get along just fine.
これからは仲良くやれそうかな
Yes. I would like for us to get along.
Like our sons do.
そう　仲良くやりたいんです
息子たちのようにね
Oh, right, there was one thing
that I wanted to check with you.
一つだけ確認しておきたかった
That honor student girl-
Fujioka Haruhi, was it?
特待生の娘さん　藤岡ハルヒといったかな
I'm thinking of having her
marry Kyoya in the future.
あの子は将来　鏡夜の嫁にと考えている
Please keep that in mind.
それだけは覚えておいてください
I guess I'm not going to get
along with you after all.
やはりあんたとは仲良くできないな
All other things aside, that is definitely
something I will not concede.
他のことはともかく　それだけは絶対譲れないですよ
Those with the wherewithal-
first, in social standing,
この私立桜蘭学院は
一に家柄　二にお金
and second, in money- spend their time
here, at the private Ouran Academy.
財あるものは暇を持つ
As such, Ouran Host Club
is where handsome boys
かくして桜蘭ホスト部とは
with too much time on their
hands entertain and charm girls,
暇を持て余す美少年たちが
who also have too much
time on their hands.
同じく暇な女生徒たちを持て成し　潤わす
It is the school's own personal,
elegant playground for the super-rich.
スーパー金持ち学校独自の
華麗なる遊戯なのである
If your fancy leads you,
please come by and visit us
気が向いたら
楽室に遊びに来てください
in Music Room #3, any time.
- All of us here at the Host Club...
我々ホスト部一同が
...from the bottom of our hearts...
心よりあなたのお越しを
"We will be waiting for you."
...will be waiting for you.
お待ちしております
扉を開けると　そこは
いつだって君のことを　僕らはここで待ってるから
嫌なことがあったのなら　僕らに話を聞かせてよ
先まで泣いていた(泣かないで)
君の悲しい顔も(すぐに)
ほら僕らならいつのまに笑顔に変える(笑顔に変える～)
また明日微笑んだ君に会えるように
澄み切った青空浮かぶ雲のように
胸いっぱい　陽の光浴びて
歩き出そう  僕と
いいね
楽しいですね
これが庶民の歌か
くだらない冗談だって　君は笑うかもしれないけれど
ただ君の喜ぶ顔が　僕らはいつも見たいだけなんだ
先まで降っていた（大丈夫）
土砂降り雨雲も（すぐに）
ほら僕らなら(どうした　光邦)笑い飛ばして
歩いて行ける(歩いて行ける～)
また明日微笑んだ君に会えるように
輪になって繋いだ手と手のぬくもりは
いつまでも忘れないように
歩き出そう  僕と
喧嘩して  すれ違う時だって(どんな時だって)
君に逢えたことに　後悔はないから(行くぞ)
また明日微笑んだ君に会えるように
澄み切った青空浮かぶ雲のように
胸いっぱい　陽の光浴びて
歩き出そう
また明日微笑んだ君に会えるように
輪になって繋いだ手と手のぬくもりは
いつまでも忘れないように(先輩～)
歩き出そう(ほらお前ら  ハルヒから離れろ)(やだよ)
また明日微笑んだ君に会えるように(楽しいね)
澄み切った青空浮かぶ雲のように(お前ら)
胸いっぱい陽の光浴びて(ハルちゃん)
歩き出そう  僕と(やれやれ)(まあ  いいっか)
诸神公关部
大海    マキ   HARERE
葉隠    阿里斯    银苹果
小袖      墨墨     花解语
黑猫与牛奶     鬼忻奈
卡卡     乐小皓    糖果酱
Syura      Mam     娜夏
ハルヒ
また明日～